

Summary: 8 Years of HR Experience

Recruitment Talent Acquisition (All Sectors) Sourcing Entire Recruitment Process Handling BFSI IT Non IT and ITES Recruitment Scheduling Interviews
Preparation of
interview guides
Month on Month
Target Achiever
Joining Formalities
Offer Letter Rollout
Appointment Letter
Generation

Employee Code Generation Induction Joining Kit Management Employee Relations Mentoring HR Best Practices Stakeholder

Management

Vendor Management Leave Management Payroll Confirmation Due Diligence Employee Performance Improvement HR Policy & Process

ANINDITA BHATTACHARYA (CHATTERJEE)

Strategic and innovative HR Executive who translates business vision into HR initiatives that improves performance, profitability, growth, and employee engagement. Empowering leader who supports companies and top executives with a unique perspective and appreciation that human capital is every organization's greatest asset. Genuine influencer who thrives on tough challenges and translates visions and strategies into actionable, value-added goals.

Experience

- Associate/Assitant Manager HR Business HR (BHR/RHR) at HDFC Life From June 2023 Till Date
- Sr. HR Executive Talent Aquisition HRBP at Bharti AXA Life Insurance From June 2022 to March 2023
- HR Executive at Star Union Dai-Ichi Life
 Insurance From January 2022 Till April 2022

Contractuals

- Worked with Connections (Freelance) and some other consultancies from April 2019 to October 2020 to July 2021.
 - Recruitment Closure acquired for various positions like Junior, Mid & Senior profile.
 - Competent in Bulk Hiring & Lateral Hiring
- HR Executive at TATA AIA Life (Team lease Payroll) from June 18 to Feb 2019
- Senior HR Executive at Sen Placement from March 17 To June 18
- HR Recruiter at Orion Edutech Pvt. Ltd. from November 14 to August 16

About me

I am a versatile recruiter, though recruitment is my major strength but I also have in depth experience in other HR activities (Generalist) throughout my career.

Current Job Role

Working for West Zone. Taking care of Entire Gujarat Region as a Regional HRBP. Taking care of Entire Employee Life Cycle from Joining till Exit.

- Entire Joining Formalities.
- Vendor Management
- ✓ Transfer / IJP / PIP Handling.
- Promotion Discussion.
- ✓ Reward and Recognition.
- ✓ Retention Handling.
- ✓ Branch Visit and Employee engagement.
- ✓ Taking session of HR Practices / STAR / Provision.
- ✓ Employee Query Resolution
- ✓ Compliance
 - POSH Handling
 - Sensitization
 - Attendance Management
 - Many More activities
- ✓ Exit Formalities

Offer Letter Generation, Stake Holder Management, 100% Manning, Goal Sheet, Budget Actual and Gap MIS, Gap Fulfilment across all 9 channels (Like Agency PP IM BANCA DD etc.) for Entire region as regional TA. Man Month Completion, MIS Maintenance Commitment vs Actual, Zoom Inductions, and Conducting Meeting with Branch Heads. Vendor Management, Drive Handling, Position opening, Job Code Creation, Requisition Raise, Retention, Attrition Management, Coordination with Regional and Zone Heads. Coordination with Vendor, Employee Referrals and Head Hunting Mass Mailing and Job Posting. Notice Period Negotiation, Separation Pending Approver.

Skill Highlights

- > HR Generalist Role : Vendor Management, Documentation , Offer letter roll out, Employe generation, reward and recognition (R & R) , Goal sheet and performance management , Rete
- ► HR Recruitment → HR Talent Acquisition (PAN India basis)
 - > Using different Job Portals for selecting the Best Resume for Recruitment Purpose
 - ➤ Scheduling interviews → Preparation of interview guides. → _Over the call interview → 1 (PR Skills in convincing the candidate)
 - > Complete Recruitment Drive handling. , Processing and Rolling out Offer Letters.
 - > Responsible for joining formalities (Follow-up with the candidates to help coordinate the Making Fitments and Salary
 - Calculations (PF included) → Background Verification and reference Check
 - Appointment Letter and Employee Code Generation
- ➤ Induction → Goal Setting → Performance management
- Release Letter processing → Attrition Handling → Retention tracker maintenance → Full and

Mobile Number: 9831367463 Email: chatterjee.anindita11@gmail.com

Contact

Phone: +91-9831367463

Email: chatterjee.anindita11@gmail.com

Present Address:

A 501 KALADEEP Apartment Satellite

Ahmedabad 380015

Permanent Address:

20 KN Sen Road KASBA Kolkata 700042



ANINDITA BHATTACHARYA (CHATTERJEE)

Personal Details

Marital Status:

Married

Date of Birth:

28th December, 1991

Nationality:

Indian

Languages

English – Read, Write, Speak Hindi – Read, Write, Speak Bengali – Read, Write, Speak

Hobbies

- Writing
- Poem Recitation
- Reading
- Surfing Internet

ACHIEVEMENT

- ♣ Recognition: Wrote a Career Counseling Column with my HR views in Ahmedabad Mirror (Times of India).
- Award: Received STAR (from TATA AIA Life) within 5 Months of joining, for successfully handling DBS project acquisition within a very short span of time.
- Appreciation: Month on Month Targer Achievier through out the career , Having excellent Recruitment Closure within Short Spans also having remarkable performance within teams and thus gifted with communication, documentation and presentation skills with interpersonal experience.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

- BCA from Meghnad Saha Institute of Technology affiliated to WBUT 2013 → Marks - 6.54 DGPA
- ◆ 12th HSE in the year 2009 from Sir Romesh Mitter girls' School under the WBCHSE → Marks- 54%
- 10th SE in the year 2007 from United Missionary Girls' High school under the WBBSE → Marks-64%

Anindita Bhattacharya (Chatterjee)

ANINDITA BHATTACHRYA (CHATTERJEE)

Mobile Number: 9831367463 Email: chatterjee.anindita11@gmail.com